<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.foxnews.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>FOX News</title>
    <link>http://www.foxnews.com/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[FOXNews.com - Breaking news and video. Latest Current News: U.S., World, Entertainment, Health, Business, Technology, Politics, Sports.]]></description>
    <image>
      <url>http://tools.foxnews.com/sites/tools.foxnews.com/files/images/fox-news-logo.png</url>
      <title>FOX News</title>
      <link>http://www.foxnews.com/</link>
    </image>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.foxnews.com/foxnews/politics" /><feedburner:info uri="foxnews/politics" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <item>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/gop-candidate-running-for-governor-presses-mcauliffe-on-climate-change.html</guid>
      <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/G0DlPHZVL0E/gop-candidate-running-for-governor-presses-mcauliffe-on-climate-change.html</link>
      <media:group>
        <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/01/28/694940094001_5301335364001_Gov--McAuliffe-Virginia-is-open-and-welcoming-to-everybody.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
        <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/01/28/60/60/694940094001_5301335364001_Gov--McAuliffe-Virginia-is-open-and-welcoming-to-everybody.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
      </media:group>
      <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/01/28/60/60/694940094001_5301335364001_Gov--McAuliffe-Virginia-is-open-and-welcoming-to-everybody.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">381a2785-c10e-4f2a-9b05-7ff0a460de27</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/gubernatorial</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/ELECTIONS/Gubernatorial</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
      <title>GOP candidate running for governor presses McAuliffe on climate change</title>
      <description>A Republican lawmaker in the 2017 Virginia governor’s race is calling for a legislative investigation into Democratic Gov. Terry McAuliffe’s order to restrict carbon emissions from power plants.

        State Sen. Frank Wagner is calling for a legislative committee hearing to investigate McAuliffe’s latest executive order, which would put more regulations on carbon emissions from electric power plants.

        McAuliffe, who’s ineligible to run again because of term limits, ordered the Virginia Department of Environmental Quality to draft a plan on the matter. This follows President Trump signing his executive order challenging the Clean Power Plan, an Obama administration act for climate change. The governor has now created his own state –based substitute.

        Wagner is one of three major GOP candidates running for the open governor’s seat.

        In the running is former Republican National Committee Chairman Ed Gillespie, and former Virginia co-chairman for Trump’s campaign, Corey Stewart. Stewart was later fired by the Trump campaign for protesting outside the RNC.

        In the latest poll conducted by Christopher Newport University, Gillespie, the establishment candidate, leads the primary with 38 percent. Stewart is polling at 11 percent and Wagner trails at 10 percent.

        “This is election-year posturing,” McAuliffe’s spokesman Brian Coy told the Richmond Times Dispatch about Wagner calling for the hearing. “The governor signed this to reduce hot air.”

        Wagner argues this investigation is not a political stunt.

        “What people perceive is their own damn business.” he told the Times Dispatch.

        He plans to call his emergency hearing before Memorial Day, just less than a month before the gubernatorial primary. Wagner says his agenda for this meeting is to see what affects these regulations would have on small businesses in Virginia.

        Democrats have two candidates in their gubernatorial primary -- Lt. Gov. Ralph Northam and former Congressman Tom Perriello, both are polling at 26 percent.

        According to Geoffrey Skelley, associate editor of Larry Sabato's Crystal Ball, this is the first time a Virginia governor’s race has had contested races for both parties. The primaries are June 13, and the next governor will be elected on Nov. 7.</description>
        <dc:creator>Charyssa Parent</dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 21:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
        <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.creator">Charyssa Parent</category>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/gop-candidate-running-for-governor-presses-mcauliffe-on-climate-change.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
        <item>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/pence-cites-trumps-leadership-in-commencement-address.html</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/Wm42oHhE0xk/pence-cites-trumps-leadership-in-commencement-address.html</link>
          <media:group>
            <media:content url="http://www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/ap17140560807236.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
            <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/60/60/ap17140560807236.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
          </media:group>
          <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/60/60/ap17140560807236.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">a55e64a2-d537-47b5-bf92-fe684b7c1509</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/education</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/US/EDUCATION</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/EXECUTIVE</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
          <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
          <title>Pence cites Trump's 'leadership' in commencement address</title>
          <description>Vice President Pence kept a busy Saturday while President Trump was overseas, espousing the president's leadership in a college commencement speech and urging Americans to thank U.S. military personnel.

            “If you see a member of the Armed Forces on Armed Forces Day … reach out and say, 'Thank you for your service,' " Pence said at Wright Patterson Air Force Base, in Ohio.

            “I couldn’t be more proud to work for a president who is so dedicated to the armed services. President Trump is overseas renewing the United States’ role as a leader among allies. … Serving with him every day, I know Trump will be the best friend the Armed Services will ever have in the White House.”

            Pence spoke just days after published news reports about him starting a so-called leadership PAC -- amid speculation he was using the group for 2020 White House run.

            The group will in fact be used to cover Pence's travel to promote Republican candidates during the 2018 congressional midterm races.

            Sources have dismissed the speculation about a presidential bid, amid Trump’s tumultuous start and such a move being unusual for a vice president.

            Early Saturday, Pence urged graduating students at Grove City College, in Pennsylvania, to become leaders and cited Trump's "leadership and perseverance" as an example.

            Trump on Saturday was in Saudi Arabia for the start of a nine-day overseas diplomatic trip, his first such since taking office in January.

            "If you aspire to lead, you'll need courage, because leadership brings both honor and opposition," Pence told hundreds of graduates and their families Saturday at the commencement.

            Pence later in the day, Pence travelled to his home state of Indiana, where he is scheduled to give the commencement speech Sunday at Norte Dame University, in South Bend.

            Grove City is a private, Christian liberal arts college with about 2,500 students and about 50 miles north of Pittsburgh.

            “Anyone who dreams big will encounter those who think small. Anyone who dares to step forward will find those who'd rather they stay put. And anyone who thinks they can will always hear from those who are sure they can't," Pence said in his commencement speech.

            He also cited Trump as "an example of leadership and perseverance" to applause from the crowd, citing the president's efforts on the economy, education, security and -- to more applause -- for standing "without apology for the sanctity of life and all the God-given liberties in the Constitution of the United States."

            "But as the president said just about a week ago in a ceremony just like this, 'Nothing worth doing ever came easy,'" Pence said. "Following your convictions means you must be willing to face criticism from those who lack the courage to do what's right,'" the vice president quoted the president as saying.

            Pence told graduates to inspire those around them, since people follow those they respect, but they should "aspire to be men and women of character" and aspire to service rather than selfish ambition.

            After his address, Pence, who was also awarded an honorary degree, stood on the platform and shook hands as each graduate passed after being handed their diplomas. Officials said the graduating class of 606 was the largest in the school's history.</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
            <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/pence-cites-trumps-leadership-in-commencement-address.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
            <item>
              <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-calls-saudi-visit-tremendous-in-critical-first-overseas-trip.html</guid>
              <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/9NbRgF2PNxc/trump-calls-saudi-visit-tremendous-in-critical-first-overseas-trip.html</link>
              <media:group>
                <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/694940094001_5442162631001_5442156833001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442162631001_5442156833001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
              </media:group>
              <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442162631001_5442156833001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
              <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">22f31756-0a22-4568-9169-20542a311e7c</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/foreign-policy</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/FOREIGN POLICY</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
              <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
              <title>Trump calls Saudi visit 'tremendous,' in critical first overseas trip</title>
              <description>President Trump on Saturday began his first overseas trip as president with a stop in Saudi Arabia, calling the visit a “tremendous day” and pledging to work with leader King Salman to bring peace to the Gulf region and forge stronger economic ties, in large part through a roughly $10 billion arms deal.

                “That was a tremendous day,” Trump said shortly after signing the arm deal. “Tremendous investments in the United States and our military. Hundreds of billions of dollars of investments into the United States and jobs, jobs, jobs."

                The arms deal is part of large, $350 billion economic package between the ally nations.

                Trump and first lady Melania Trump were greeted in Saudi Arabia at the airport by 81-year King Salman, in a red carpet ceremony that also included a military flyover in which several jets left red, white and blue streamers.

                Trump called his visit to Saudi Arabia "a great honor" and joined the king in a brief coffee ceremony at the airport terminal before heading to his hotel and other official events of the day.

                After signing the deal and talking with top Saudi leaders, Trump and the first lady are scheduled to participate in a royal banquet dinner and a museum tour at the Murabba Palace in Riyadh.

                Before the dinner, Trump participated in a traditional Saudi "war dance," performed this time to celebrate the countries' renewed friendship.

                Trump is also scheduled to make a major speech Sunday in which he’s expected to show support for America’s Persian Gulf allies, a likely reset after months of talk about Muslim extremism.

                The president’s next stop in his nine-day tour will be Israel, where he will have an audience with Pope Francis at the Vatican, then meet with allies at a NATO summit in Brussels and the Group of 7 wealthy nations in Sicily.

                “Great to be in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia,” Trump tweeted upon landing on Air Force One. “Looking forward to the afternoon and evening ahead.”

                The first lady wore a black pantsuit with a golden belt and did not cover her head for the arrival, consistent with custom for foreign dignitaries visiting Saudi Arabia.

                Trump shook hands with the king, compared to then-President Barack Obama in 2009 appearing to bow before then-King Abdullah, a move some viewed as a sign of American weakness.

                Trump, during his winning presidential campaign and in the first several months of his presidency, has argued that the United States can no longer be the world’s police officer and that other nations must become more self-sufficient in efforts to combat such terror networks as al Qaeda and the Islamic State and in protecting themselves against rogue nations like Iran and North Korea.

                After two days of meetings in Riyadh, Trump will travel to Israel where he’ll have an audience with Pope Francis at the Vatican, then meet with allies at a NATO summit in Brussels and the Group of 7 wealthy nations in Sicily.

                The multi-billion dollar arms deal “in the clearest terms possible” shows the United States’ commitment to Saudi Arabia and other Gulf partners and expands economic opportunities, the White House said.

                The deal will include tanks, combat ships, missile defense systems, radar and communications and cybersecurity technology. And it will support tens-of-thousands of new jobs in the U.S. defense industrial base, the White House said.

                Trump did not address the cameras. But Secretary of State Rex Tillerson and Saudi Foreign Minister Abdel al Jubeir held a joint press conference.

                Jubeir said Trump "certainly has the vision and, we believe, strength to bring about Middle East peace.”

                He also called Trump’s trip a “truly historic visit.”

                Said Tillerson: “We’re very proud of this relationship we're embarking on.”

                He also took a question about a recent news report about somebody within the White House being a person of interest amid ongoing investigations into whether Trump and his associates colluded with Russia to help Trump win the 2016 presidential race.

                Tillerson said he had “no knowledge” about such a person of interest.

                White House officials hope the trip gives Trump the opportunity to recalibrate after one of the most difficult stretches of his young presidency. The White House badly bungled the president's stunning firing of FBI Director James Comey, who was overseeing the federal government’s investigation into possible Russia collusion.

                Trump on Sunday will also hold meetings with more than 50 Arab and Muslim leaders converging on Riyadh for a regional summit focused largely on combating the Islamic State and other extremist groups.

                Still, the centerpiece of Trump's visit to Saudi Arabia will likely be the speech Sunday at the Arab-Islamic-American summit.

                White House aides view the address as a counter to Obama's 2009 speech to the Muslim world, which Trump criticized as too apologetic for U.S. actions in the region.

                Trump will call for unity in the fight against radicalism in the Muslim world, casting the challenge as a "battle between good and evil" and urging Arab leaders to "drive out the terrorists from your places of worship," according to a draft of the speech obtained by The Associated Press. The draft notably refrains from mentioning democracy and human rights — topics Arab leaders often view as U.S. moralizing — in favor of the more limited goals of peace and stability.

                It also abandons some of the harsh anti-Muslim rhetoric that defined Trump's presidential campaign and does not contain the words "radical Islamic terror," a phrase Trump repeatedly criticized Hillary Clinton for not using during last year's campaign.</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 15:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
                <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-calls-saudi-visit-tremendous-in-critical-first-overseas-trip.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                <item>
                  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-shakes-hands-with-saudi-leader-doesnt-bow-as-obama-appeared-to-do.html</guid>
                  <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/PzG8NJrN8Yw/trump-shakes-hands-with-saudi-leader-doesnt-bow-as-obama-appeared-to-do.html</link>
                  <media:group>
                    <media:content url="http://www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/split.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                    <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/60/60/split.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                  </media:group>
                  <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/www.foxnews.com/content/dam/fox-news/images/2017/05/20/60/60/split.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">99dc3cb4-c0a8-4e2f-b3ff-a5b4d670fe3f</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/foreign-policy</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/FOREIGN POLICY</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                  <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                  <title>Trump shakes hands with Saudi leader, doesn't bow as Obama appeared to do</title>
                  <description>President Trump upon arriving in Saudi Arabia on Saturday did not bow to the Gulf leader as former President Barack Obama appeared to do -- a move interpreted as American weakness.

                    In 2009, Obama appeared to bow to then-Saudi leader King Abdullah at a G-20 summit in London.

                    Videos show Obama bending at the waist toward the king. The White House at the time purportedly denied that the president had bowed, with a source saying Obama was taller than the king, so he had to lean.

                    Trump's visit to Saudi Arabia marks the start to his nine-day, overseas tour that will also take him to Israel and Europe. The international trip is Trump’s first since taking office in January.

                    Trump was greeted at the Saudi airport with an elaborate ceremony, punctuated by a military flyover and a handshake from Saudi King Salman.

                    First lady Melania Trump wore a black pantsuit with a golden belt and did not cover her head for the arrival, consistent with custom for foreign dignitaries visiting Saudi Arabia.

                    The 81-year-old King Salman greeted Trump at the airport. The two leaders exchanged pleasantries and Trump said it was "a great honor" to be there.

                    “Two things need to happen,” Zuhdi Jasser, founder of the American Islamic Forum for Democracy, told Fox News on Saturday about Trump’s trip. “President Trump needs to shore up our alliance with the Sunnis who feel abandon, and that starts with Saudi Arabia. And in the short-term, he needs to create a coalition that will decimate and defeat ISIS.”

                    Obama critics said the former president suggested several times in 2009, just after getting elected, that the United States owed the Arab world an apology.

                    “There have been times when America has shown arrogance … even dismissiveness,” Obama said that year in France.

                    Upon Trump’s arrival Saturday, Several jets then flew overhead leaving a red, white and blue trail.

                    Saudi Arabia offered Trump the elaborate welcome ahead of his two-day stay. Billboards featuring images of Trump and the king dotted the highways of Riyadh, emblazoned with the motto "Together we prevail."

                    Trump's luxury hotel was bathed in red, white and blue lights and, at times, an image of the president's face.

                    Trump and the king met briefly in the airport terminal for a coffee ceremony before the president headed to his hotel before the day's other meetings.</description>
                    <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
                    <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-shakes-hands-with-saudi-leader-doesnt-bow-as-obama-appeared-to-do.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                    <item>
                      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-in-saudi-arabia-signs-110b-arms-deal-with-persian-gulf-ally.html</guid>
                      <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/g8Q7xSJ8fQc/trump-in-saudi-arabia-signs-110b-arms-deal-with-persian-gulf-ally.html</link>
                      <media:group>
                        <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                        <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                      </media:group>
                      <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">e7a4432c-d448-43d2-baeb-f6d15a9741c1</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/world-regions/middle-east</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/foreign-policy</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/WORLD/WORLD REGIONS/Middle East</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/FOREIGN POLICY</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/EXECUTIVE</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                      <title>Trump in Saudi Arabia signs $110B arms deal with Persian Gulf ally</title>
                      <description>President Trump in Saudi Arabia on Saturday signed a nearly $110 billion arms deal to help the Persian Gulf ally with its military-defense system.

                        "That was a tremendous day," Trump said after signing the deal with Saudi leader King Salman. "Tremendous investments in the United States. Hundreds of billions of dollars of investments into the United States and jobs, jobs, jobs."

                        The White House says the package includes defense equipment and other support to help the Arab nation and the rest of the Gulf region fight again terrorism and the threat of a nuclear-armed Iran, according to the White House.

                        Trump during his winning presidential campaign and in the first several months of his presidency has argued the United States can no longer be the world’s police officer and that other nations must become more self-sufficient in efforts to combat terrorism and in protecting themselves against rogue nations like Iran and North Korea. Trump arrived in Saudi Arabia early Saturday as the start to his nine-day, overseas tour that will also take him to Israel and Europe. The international trip is Trump’s first since taking office in January.

                        “Great to be in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia,” Trump tweeted upon landing in Air Force One. “Looking forward to the afternoon and evening ahead.”

                        Trump is expected to pledge his respect and support to Saudi leaders and to the region, after months of harsh anti-Muslim rhetoric.

                        Trump greeted at the Saudi airport with an elaborate ceremony, punctuated by a military flyover and a handshake from Saudi King Salman.

                        First lady Melania Trump wore a black pantsuit with a golden belt and did not cover her head for the arrival, consistent with custom for foreign dignitaries visiting Saudi Arabia.

                        In 2015, her husband had, in a tweet, criticized former first lady Michelle Obama for not wearing a headscarf during a visit to the kingdom.

                        After two days of meetings in Riyadh, Trump will travel to Israel, have an audience with Pope Francis at the Vatican, then meet with allies at a NATO summit in Brussels and the Group of 7 wealthy nations in Sicily.

                        The multi-billion dollar defense deal “in the clearest terms possible” shows the United States’ commitment to Saudi Arabia and other Gulf partners and expands economic opportunities, the White House said. The deal will also supporting tens-of-thousands of new jobs in the U.S. defense industrial base, the White House also said.

                        The package includes tanks, combat ships, missile defense systems, radar and communications and cybersecurity technology.

                        The 81-year-old King Salman greeted Trump at the airport. The two leaders exchanged pleasantries and Trump said it was "a great honor" to be there.

                        Several jets then flew overhead leaving a red, white and blue trail.

                        Saudi Arabia offered Trump the elaborate welcome ahead of his two-day stay. Billboards featuring images of Trump and the king dotted the highways of Riyadh, emblazoned with the motto "Together we prevail."

                        Trump's luxury hotel was bathed in red, white and blue lights and, at times, an image of the president's face.

                        Trump and the king met briefly in the airport terminal for a coffee ceremony before the president headed to his hotel before the day's other meetings.

                        White House Chief of Staff Reince Priebus told reporters on Air Force One that Trump spent the flight meeting with staff, working on his upcoming speech to the Muslim world and getting a little sleep.

                        White House officials hope the trip gives Trump the opportunity to recalibrate after one of the most difficult stretches of his young presidency. The White House badly bungled the president's stunning firing of FBI Director James Comey, who was overseeing the federal investigation into possible ties between Trump's campaign and Russia. On Wednesday, the Justice Department relented to calls from Democrats to name a special counsel, tapping former FBI chief Robert Mueller to lead the probe.

                        After spending much of Saturday meeting with King Salman and other members of the royal family, Trump was to end the day at a banquet dinner at the Murabba Palace. On Sunday, he'll hold meetings with more than 50 Arab and Muslim leaders converging on Riyadh for a regional summit focused largely on combating the Islamic State and other extremist groups.

                        Trump dodged one potential land mine when Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir, who has been indicted on war crime and genocide charges, announced that he would not attend the summit for personal reasons.

                        The centerpiece of Trump's visit to Saudi Arabia will be a speech Sunday at the Arab-Islamic-American summit. White House aides view the address as a counter to Obama's 2009 speech to the Muslim world, which Trump criticized as too apologetic for U.S. actions in the region.

                        Trump will call for unity in the fight against radicalism in the Muslim world, casting the challenge as a "battle between good and evil" and urging Arab leaders to "drive out the terrorists from your places of worship," according to a draft of the speech obtained by The Associated Press. The draft notably refrains from mentioning democracy and human rights — topics Arab leaders often view as U.S. moralizing — in favor of the more limited goals of peace and stability.

                        It also abandons some of the harsh anti-Muslim rhetoric that defined Trump's presidential campaign and does not contain the words "radical Islamic terror," a phrase Trump repeatedly criticized Hillary Clinton for not using during last year's campaign.</description>
                        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 13:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
                        <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                        <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/trump-in-saudi-arabia-signs-110b-arms-deal-with-persian-gulf-ally.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                        <item>
                          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/melania-trump-forgoes-wearing-headscarf-in-saudi-arabia-trip.html</guid>
                          <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/m0dSvdxJVQo/melania-trump-forgoes-wearing-headscarf-in-saudi-arabia-trip.html</link>
                          <media:group>
                            <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                            <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                          </media:group>
                          <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/20/60/60/694940094001_5442084689001_5442080806001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">5bcd21b4-8388-481a-a44c-2abf0be34275</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/world/world-regions/middle-east</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/us/religion/islam</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/foreign-policy</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/first-family</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/WORLD/WORLD REGIONS/Middle East</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/US/RELIGION/Islam</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/FOREIGN POLICY</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/EXECUTIVE/First Family</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                          <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                          <title>Melania Trump forgoes wearing headscarf in Saudi Arabia trip</title>
                          <description>Melania Trump went without a headscarf as she arrived in Saudi Arabia Saturday with her husband.

                            The first lady wore long sleeves and pants in keeping with the strict dress code that Saudi Arabia enforces for its female citizens but she did not cover her head. Her long hair blew freely in the breeze as she stepped off Air Force One at King Khalid International Airport in the capital city of Riyadh.

                            Related Image
                            President Donald Trump and first lady Melania arrive for a welcome ceremony at the Royal Terminal of King Khalid International Airport, Saturday, May 20, 2017, in Riyadh. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)Expand / Collapse
                            President Donald Trump and first lady Melania arrive for a welcome ceremony at the Royal Terminal of King Khalid International Airport, Saturday, May 20, 2017, in Riyadh. (AP Photo/Evan Vucci)  (Copyright 2017 The Associated Press. All rights reserved.)
                            President Trump criticized former first lady Michelle Obama for not wearing a headscarf during a January 2015 visit to Saudi Arabia with then-President Barack Obama.

                            While many people applauded Mrs. Obama’s decision, Trump tweeted in 2015 that the people of Saudi Arabia “were insulted.”

                            Related Image
                            U.S. President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama are greeted by Saudi Arabia's King Salman (R) as they arrive at King Khalid International Airport in Riyadh, January 27, 2015. Obama is stopping in Saudi Arabia on his way back to Washington from India to pay his condolences over the death of King Abdullah and to hold bilateral meetings with King Salman.   REUTERS/Jim Bourg     (SAUDI ARABIA - Tags: POLITICS ROYALS TPX IMAGES OF THE DAY BUSINESS) - RTR4N4SFExpand / Collapse
                            U.S. President Barack Obama and first lady Michelle Obama are greeted by Saudi Arabia's King Salman (R) as they arrive at King Khalid International Airport in Riyadh, January 27, 2015. Obama is stopping in Saudi Arabia on his way back to Washington from India to pay his condolences over the death of King Abdullah and to hold bilateral meetings with King Salman. REUTERS/Jim Bourg (SAUDI ARABIA - Tags: POLITICS ROYALS TPX IMAGES OF THE DAY BUSINESS) - RTR4N4SF
                            "Many people are saying it was wonderful that Mrs. Obama refused to wear a scarf in Saudi Arabia, but they were insulted. We have enuf enemies," he tweeted, using a short-hand spelling for "enough."

                            Follow
                            Donald J. Trump ✔ @realDonaldTrump
                            Many people are saying it was wonderful that Mrs. Obama refused to wear a scarf in Saudi Arabia, but they were insulted.We have enuf enemies
                            8:40 AM - 29 Jan 2015
                            4,197 4,197 Retweets   2,120 2,120 likes
                            Twitter Ads info and Privacy
                            Under the kingdom's strict dress code for women, Saudi women and most female visitors are required to wear a loose, black robe, known as an abaya, in public. Most women in Saudi Arabia also cover their hair and face with a veil known as the niqab.

                            But covering one's head is not required for foreigners, and some Western women choose to forego the headscarf while in Saudi Arabia.

                            Earlier this year, British Prime Minister Theresa May and German Chancellor Angela Merkel also shunned head coverings, showing how common it is for high-level female visitors to skip wearing a headscarf or an abaya, the loose-fitting, black robe worn by Saudi women.

                            Michelle Obama did not cover her head when she accompanied then-President Barack Obama on a condolence visit in January 2015 after the death of King Abdullah. And during her time as first lady, Laura Bush generally went without covering her head, though she once briefly donned a head scarf she received as a gift.

                            As Obama's secretary of state, Hillary Clinton also did not cover her head on visits to Saudi Arabia.

                            President Trump's daughter, Ivanka, a senior White House adviser who is accompanying her father, also did not cover her head.

                            Saudi Arabia is the first stop on a four-nation, five-stop tour that will also take Trump to Israel, Italy and Belgium before President Trump returns to the White House at the end of next week. The first lady is joining the president for the entire trip.</description>
                            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 11:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
                            <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                            <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/20/melania-trump-forgoes-wearing-headscarf-in-saudi-arabia-trip.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                            <item>
                              <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/karl-rove-new-york-times-story-troubling-much-bigger-than-wash-post.html</guid>
                              <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/-asJvmRTBoQ/karl-rove-new-york-times-story-troubling-much-bigger-than-wash-post.html</link>
                              <media:group>
                                <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/694940094001_5441719092001_5441712256001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                                <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441719092001_5441712256001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                              </media:group>
                              <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441719092001_5441712256001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">56201af8-f86f-4f2c-8cec-ccb6b1a8b8e7</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/EXECUTIVE/White House</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                              <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                              <title>Karl Rove: New York Times story 'troubling,' much bigger than Wash Post</title>
                              <description>The New York Times report about President Trump telling the Russians in the Oval Office that firing FBI Director James Comey had relieved “great pressure” on him is a bigger story than the Washington Post’s Russia report, said Fox News contributor Karl Rove on ‘The Story with Martha MacCallum’ on Friday.

                                “It’s a confirmation of what we knew. Holt interviewed Trump who said, in essence, ‘I fired him because he was a pain,’” said Rove. “The direct connection between I faced great pressure because of Russia and that’s taken off and it just sounds unseemly.”

                                Another troubling aspect of the New York Times story, according to Rove, is that the notes were taken at a meeting attended by only four officials: Trump, Vice President Mike Pence, Sec. of State Rex Tillerson, and National Security Advisor H.R. McMaster.

                                “The idea that private notes from a presidential meeting like this would be circulated. This is in violation of several laws, they better find out who is doing this kind of stuff. Just as they could leak this to the press, someone could also leak details of the White House meeting to our adversaries just as easy as they leak this to the public to the Washington Post or the New York Times””

                                “Let’s be clear. Person of interest means it’s somebody the FBI wants to talk to. There’s a big difference between that and being the subject of the investigation or the target of the investigation,” said Rove. “I think it’s overblown.”

                                MacCallum asked Rove and Fox News contributor Marie Harf if we will get some answers from Comey when he testifies before the Senate Intelligence Committee after Memorial Day.

                                “This is going to be must-watch TV,” said Harf, who used to work in the Obama administration. “It will be very interesting to see how Comey plays this hearing, how forthcoming he is.”</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 23:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
                                <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                                <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/karl-rove-new-york-times-story-troubling-much-bigger-than-wash-post.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                                <item>
                                  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/russia-investigation-ex-fbi-chief-james-comey-to-testify-before-senate-intel-committee-in-open-session.html</guid>
                                  <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/BiHlC9TRrJY/russia-investigation-ex-fbi-chief-james-comey-to-testify-before-senate-intel-committee-in-open-session.html</link>
                                  <media:group>
                                    <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/694940094001_5441655428001_5441643015001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                                    <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441655428001_5441643015001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                                  </media:group>
                                  <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441655428001_5441643015001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">18bf9b17-fc0f-41c3-91ee-51e8bc09766d</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/executive/white-house</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/EXECUTIVE/White House</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                                  <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                                  <title>Russia investigation: Ex-FBI chief James Comey to testify before Senate Intel Committee in open session</title>
                                  <description>Former FBI Director James Comey will testify before the Senate Intelligence Committee in public sometime after Memorial Day.

                                    The committee's chairman, Sen. Richard Burr, and the ranking Democrat, Sen. Mark Warner, announced Friday that Comey will testify in an open setting before the committee. The date of the hearing has not yet been set.

                                    Burr says the committee wants to hear from Comey on his role in the development of the U.S. intelligence agencies' assessment that Russia interfered in last year's election.

                                    He says he hopes Comey's testimony will answer some of the questions that have arisen since Comey was suddenly dismissed last week by President Donald Trump.

                                    This news after reports Friday in the New York Times and the Washington Post about the fallout from Trump's firing of Comey, as well as the inquiry into Russia's role in the 2016 election and possible collusion with the Trump campaign.

                                    The Times reported Friday that Trump told the Russians that recently fired FBI Director James Comey was a "nut job" whose ouster relieved "great pressure" on him. The Washington Post reported that a senior Trump administration official is now a "person of interest" in the Russia probe.

                                    Maryland Rep. Elijah Cummings called Trump's reported comment about Comey "astonishing and extremely troubling."

                                    Cummings said the committee's GOP chairman, Utah Rep. Jason Chaffetz, "should ... have his subpoena pen ready" to obtain any White House documents related to Trump's meeting with the Russian foreign minister and ambassador.

                                    Chaffetz has scheduled a hearing on Comey's firing next Wednesday, although it's not clear if Comey will testify.

                                    Meanwhile, Senate Judiciary Committee Chairman Chuck Grassley and Ranking Member Dianne Feinstein today released a statement after Comey declined to testify before their committee that reads in part:

                                    “We’re extremely disappointed in James Comey’s decision not to testify voluntarily before the Judiciary Committee. There is no reason he can’t testify before both the Intelligence and Judiciary Committees, particularly given that the Judiciary Committee is the FBI’s primary oversight committee with broad jurisdiction over federal law enforcement, FISA and the nomination of the next FBI director....He should reconsider his decision.”

                                    Former FBI Director Robert Mueller was named Special Counsel for the Russia investigation on Wednesday.</description>
                                    <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 23:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
                                    <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                                    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/russia-investigation-ex-fbi-chief-james-comey-to-testify-before-senate-intel-committee-in-open-session.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                                    <item>
                                      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/george-soros-boosts-another-da-candidate-in-philadelphia-race.html</guid>
                                      <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/6KBUeNnb7wc/george-soros-boosts-another-da-candidate-in-philadelphia-race.html</link>
                                      <media:group>
                                        <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/03/15/694940094001_5360478910001_GOP-push-to-probe-federal-funding-for-Soros-backed-groups.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                                        <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/03/15/60/60/694940094001_5360478910001_GOP-push-to-probe-federal-funding-for-Soros-backed-groups.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                                      </media:group>
                                      <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/03/15/60/60/694940094001_5360478910001_GOP-push-to-probe-federal-funding-for-Soros-backed-groups.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">52a6d51d-438a-40ea-8fb4-4ea0415511e8</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics/elections/democrats</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS/ELECTIONS/Democrats</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics/elections</category>
                                      <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                                      <title>George Soros boosts another DA candidate, in Philadelphia race</title>
                                      <description>Big bucks from George Soros helped turn a Pennsylvania district attorney election on its head, in the latest example of the liberal billionaire’s influence in local U.S. politics.

                                        On April 28, Soros poured nearly $1.5 million into the Philadelphia Justice and Public Safety PAC, which supported candidate Larry Krasner in the Democratic primary. Krasner won on Tuesday, and by a wide margin.

                                        He is expected to win the general election this fall, as Philadelphia is a Democratic stronghold. How much of a difference the PAC money made is unclear, but the cash infusion helped pay for TV commercials, campaign literature, and online ads to promote the candidacy of the civil rights attorney who has never worked as a prosecutor.

                                        The race marked the first time a super PAC has supported a D.A. candidate in Philadelphia.

                                        Krasner, as the Daily Caller puts it, benefited from “the kind of capital typically reserved for important national political campaigns.”

                                        But it’s not the first time Soros has pumped cash into local D.A. races, in an apparent bid to shape the approach to law enforcement on the ground level.

                                        Last August, Politico reported that Soros had channeled more than $3 million into seven local district-attorney campaigns in six states over the past year.

                                        The Washington Times looked at all of 2015 and 2016, reporting Soros sunk more than $7 million into at least 11 local prosecutor races in 10 states in that period. The report described it as part of “an effort to implement criminal justice reform from the inside.”

                                        One race Soros supported in Texas already has led to a policy change. Kim Ogg, who won the election for district attorney of Harris County last fall, after a cash influx from Soros, announced she will decriminalize small amounts of marijuana in the Houston area.

                                        That goes against President Trump’s Attorney General Jeff Sessions, who has taken a tough stance on marijuana and has said he is not in favor legalizing the drug.

                                        Fox News reached out to Soros for comment regarding the latest election. The Philadelphia PAC’s treasurer Whitney Tymas replied to Fox News and cited Krasner’s platform as the reason for supporting him.

                                        “Philadelphia Justice and Public Safety supported Larry Krasner for district attorney because of his commitment to public safety and criminal justice reform,” Tymas said.

                                        After his victory, Krasner spoke to reporters and said the Soros cash wouldn’t affect his policies. “I don’t have to pick up the phone for anyone,” Krasner told reporters. “It’s no disrespect to Mr. Soros, whom I have never met, or his organization, but the bottom line is I have held these views for a long time.”

                                        Ben Waxman, a spokesman for Krasner’s campaign, told Fox News, “Larry Krasner has been a civil rights attorney in Philadelphia for over 30 years. He has handled many cases and has a deep amount of criminal justice experience. In addition, he is an activist. He has been doing and saying the same thing for 30 years.”

                                        He added, “Other candidates spent a large amount of money in this campaign. The reason Krasner won is because of his ideas on criminal justice reform.”

                                        When asked if Krasner appreciated the support offered by Soros and the Philadelphia Justice and Public Safety PAC, Waxman said the campaign had a strong coalition of voters.

                                        “He is thankful to all of his supporters,” he said, “this deep Philly-based coalition including his volunteers and his staff.”</description>
                                        <dc:creator>Jason Kopp</dc:creator>
                                        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 20:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
                                        <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                                        <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.creator">Jason Kopp</category>
                                        <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/george-soros-boosts-another-da-candidate-in-philadelphia-race.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                                        <item>
                                          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/trumps-first-foreign-trip-scheduled-stops-in-saudi-arabia-israel-and-beyond.html</guid>
                                          <link>http://feeds.foxnews.com/~r/foxnews/politics/~3/t1Tys_oldgc/trumps-first-foreign-trip-scheduled-stops-in-saudi-arabia-israel-and-beyond.html</link>
                                          <media:group>
                                            <media:content url="http://media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/694940094001_5441217114001_5441196698001-vs.jpg" medium="image" isDefault="true" />
                                            <media:content url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441217114001_5441196698001-vs.jpg" medium="image" width="60" height="60" />
                                          </media:group>
                                          <media:thumbnail url="http://a57.foxnews.com/media2.foxnews.com/BrightCove/694940094001/2017/05/19/60/60/694940094001_5441217114001_5441196698001-vs.jpg" width="60" height="60" />
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.identifier">e464cc7e-0333-4580-84ad-5c7d46d19307</category>
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">fox-news/politics</category>
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/taxonomy">/FOX NEWS/POLITICS</category>
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/prism.channel">fnc</category>
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/section-path">fnc/politics</category>
                                          <category domain="foxnews.com/content-type">article</category>
                                          <title>Trump's first foreign trip: Scheduled stops in Saudi Arabia, Israel and beyond</title>
                                          <description>President Donald Trump leaves the United States today for his first overseas trip as commander-in-chief, with a full itinerary of stops throughout the Middle East and Europe.

                                            His trip begins Friday with a stop in Saudi Arabia, followed by planned visits to Israel and the Vatican. Trump will later attend the 28th NATO summit in Brussels, Belgium, and the 43rd G7 summit in Taormina, Italy.

                                            The president's travel comes on the heels of a number of highly publicized controversies, including the recent firing of FBI Director James Comey.

                                            Below is a look at what the president has lined up so far.

                                            Saudi Arabia

                                            Trump will arrive in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, where there will be an arrival ceremony, National Security Advisor H.R. McMaster said at a news conference Tuesday.

                                            He's slated to have coffee with King Salman, go to bilateral meetings with members of the royal family and attend a royal banquet, McMaster told reporters.

                                            The president will also attend "a signing ceremony of several agreements that will further solidify U.S.-Saudi security and economic cooperation."

                                            Trump and first lady Melania Trump will partake in an official dinner with the Saudi royal family that evening, according to McMaster.

                                            The next day, Trump will meet with leaders of the Gulf Cooperation Council, McMaster said. That afternoon, Trump is slated to have lunch with leaders from dozens of Muslim countries, "where he will deliver an inspiring, yet direct speech on the need to confront radical ideology," according to McMaster.

                                            Trump is also expected to later participate in "the inauguration of a new center intended to fight radicalism and promote moderation" as well as in a Twitter forum.

                                            Israel

                                            Trump will meet with Israel President Reuven Rivlin in Jerusalem and plans to lay a wreath at Yad Vashem, a Holocaust memorial.

                                            Trump is also expected to give remarks at the Israeli Museum before later meeting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu. He and Melania will also attend a private dinner with Netanyahu and the prime minister's wife, Sara.

                                            Trump will meet Palestinian Authority leader Mahmoud Abbas in Bethlehem the next morning and "convey his administration's eagerness to facilitate an agreement that ends the [Israeli/Palestinian] conflict," McMaster said.

                                            Other planned stops include the Church of the Holy Sepulcher and the Western Wall, where Trump will pray.

                                            PUTIN ON TRUMP-LAVROV MEETING: I'LL HAND OVER RECORDS

                                            The Vatican

                                            The next day, Trump is going to have a meeting with Pope Francis at the Vatican, McMaster said. "He looks forward to celebrating the rich contributions of Catholics to America and to the world, and to discussing a range of issues of mutual concern," he explained.

                                            Trump is planning to tour St. Peter's. He will also meet Italian President Sergio Mattarella.

                                            TRUMP'S AGENDA AT RISK AFTER SERIES OF CONTROVERSIES

                                            Belgium

                                            Trump will meet King Philippe and Queen Mathilde, as well as Prime Minister Charles Michel.

                                            He will later meet with the presidents of the European Union and the European Council.

                                            He's expected to later have a "working lunch" with newly elected French President Emmanuel Macron, McMaster said.

                                            Trump will follow that by delivering remarks at the unveilling of a NATO memorial and will reaffirm the United States' commitment to NATO, McMaster said. Trump, along with Secretary of Defense James Mattis, will also attend a meeting and dinner with NATO leaders.

                                            Italy

                                            Trump is expected to then travel to the 43rd G7 summit, which will be held May 26-27 in Taormina on the island of Sicily.  In the meetings, he'll "press America's economic agenda and call for greater security cooperation," McMaster said.

                                            On the first night of the G7, he'll also go see La Scala Philharmonic Orchestra and attend a dinner hosted by Italian President Sergio Mattarella.

                                            Trump is planning to speak to U.S. troops at Sigonella Naval Air Station before he leaves Italy.</description>
                                            <dc:creator>Zoe Szathmary</dc:creator>
                                            <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 20:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
                                            <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.source">FoxNews.com</category>
                                            <category domain="foxnews.com/metadata/dc.creator">Zoe Szathmary</category>
                                            <feedburner:origLink>http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2017/05/19/trumps-first-foreign-trip-scheduled-stops-in-saudi-arabia-israel-and-beyond.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
                                          </channel>
                                        </rss>
